<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jackass Theology</title>
	<atom:link href="http://jackasstheology.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<description>For Love, Joy, Peace, and Basic Human Dignity</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 16:43:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-LOGO_BLK_BG_Square.jpg?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Jackass Theology</title>
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">156140201</site>	<item>
		<title>You Can&#8217;t Write about Jackassery without Being a Jackass</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/12/04/you-cant-write-about-jackassery-without-being-a-jackass/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/12/04/you-cant-write-about-jackassery-without-being-a-jackass/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 16:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Types of Jackass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John MacArthur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phil Johnson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1750</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;d like to bring you into my struggle with this blog a bit. A few weeks ago, I wrote about some very demeaning statements John MacArthur and Phil Johnson made about Beth Moore. I said their comments were cruel and seemed designed to wound. I still stand by those statements. But here&#8217;s the thing. I&#8217;m [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I&#8217;d like to bring you into my struggle with this blog a bit. A few weeks ago, I wrote about some <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/19/john-macarthurs-disgusting-comment-go-home-beth-moore/">very demeaning statements</a> John MacArthur and Phil Johnson made about Beth Moore. I said their comments were cruel and seemed designed to wound. I still stand by those statements. But here&#8217;s the thing. I&#8217;m pretty sure I myself was a jackass in my response. </p>



<p>When a person decides to start a blog about being a jackass, one quickly discovers that it&#8217;s impossible to point out jackassery without frequently dipping into the very evil one is trying to eradicate. Turns out, that&#8217;s Jackass Theology Blogging 101. </p>



<p>If you&#8217;ve been around for a minute, you know that Ryan and I have <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/01/02/what-is-jackass-theology%ef%bb%bf/">tried to be very confessional</a> throughout. We can clearly see the jackass tendencies in ourselves and in each other, so we try to write about that rather than always pointing out the jackassery we see in the world around us. </p>



<p>But I know we don&#8217;t always get it right.</p>



<p>I have re-read my post about John MacArthur many times, and I keep praying through whether or not the things I said were appropriate. Am I calling attention to an example of the ways our pursuit of orthodoxy can become a manifestation of the &#8220;works of the flesh&#8221; rather than the &#8220;fruit of the Spirit&#8221;? I think so. Most of you thought so as well. But then some of you saw my post playing into &#8220;outrage culture&#8221; or &#8220;cancel culture.&#8221; Were my words any better than the demeaning words I was hoping to call us away from? I honestly don&#8217;t know for sure (again, I keep re-reading and am not myself convinced), but I am confident that I didn&#8217;t get it all right. I tried to affirm my appreciation for MacArthur&#8217;s ministry and tried to use it as a means of calling us on to something better than what he did that one day. I&#8217;m sure I botched it. He loves Jesus, and I don&#8217;t want to have torn him down. I&#8217;m sincerely sorry for the ways my post tore down anything that&#8217;s good and belongs to the kingdom of God.</p>



<p><a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/18/superhuman-jackass-guy/">Here&#8217;s something I know for sure: I am not God</a>. Jesus would get this blog exactly right at every turn. I know I&#8217;m not going to be able to do that. However, I don&#8217;t believe that making mistakes is reason enough for burning the whole thing to the ground. Instead, I think it&#8217;s a great reminder that I am not God, and that I need to continue to confess and seek him. I absolutely believe that examples of our own jackassery are more powerful than examples of the jackassery in Christian celebrities. My own examples get far fewer clicks, but they&#8217;re more meaningful. And prevalent. </p>



<p>I still think it&#8217;s worth fighting jackassery. But I know we&#8217;ll constantly need to acknowledge the ways it creeps out of our own mouths and actions. Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn helpfully said, &#8220;The line separating good and evil passes not through states, nor between classes, nor between political parties either – but right through every human heart.&#8221; If that&#8217;s not true, I don&#8217;t know what is. And truly, the line separating jackasses from Spirit-filled people does not pass through theological camps or denominations, but right through every human heart. Including my own. Especially my own. </p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;The line separating jackasses from Spirit-filled people does not pass through theological camps or denominations, but right through every human heart. Including my own. Especially my own.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CThe+line+separating+jackasses+from+Spirit-filled+people+does+not+pass+through+theological+camps+or+denominations%2C+but+right+through+every+human+heart.+Including+my+own.+Especially+my+own.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-se" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-se&t=%E2%80%9CThe+line+separating+jackasses+from+Spirit-filled+people+does+not+pass+through+theological+camps+or+denominations%2C+but+right+through+every+human+heart.+Including+my+own.+Especially+my+own.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>We&#8217;re still trying to learn how to expose jackassery and say &#8220;that&#8217;s not okay&#8221; and &#8220;that&#8217;s not from God&#8221; while keeping ourselves unstained from jackassery. I&#8217;d love to say that we&#8217;ll find the balance at some point, but I know that&#8217;s not true. We&#8217;re not Jesus, and he&#8217;s the only one who completely avoids jackassery. But he&#8217;s also the one who <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/solutions/">heals jackassery</a>, so there&#8217;s a lot of hope there. </p>



<p>The reason we&#8217;re fighting this battle is because we believe we all need to let go of <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/20/the-sin-of-certainty/">our petty doctrinal certitude</a> and <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/18/superhuman-jackass-guy/">our need to be right</a> and instead cling to Jesus. And that&#8217;s a battle worth fighting. We should expect that along the way we ourselves will need to acknowledge times we&#8217;ve co-opted the moral high ground and begun to speak with the voice of the jackass. After all, we need Jesus as much as anyone. He&#8217;s the point of it all anyway, and I&#8217;m glad for a chance to acknowledge my dependence on him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/12/04/you-cant-write-about-jackassery-without-being-a-jackass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>John MacArthur&#8217;s Disgusting Comment: Go Home, Beth Moore</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/19/john-macarthurs-disgusting-comment-go-home-beth-moore/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/19/john-macarthurs-disgusting-comment-go-home-beth-moore/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 21:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John MacArthur]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1742</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This is a weird post for me to write. Maybe I should first tell you that I graduated from John MacArthur&#8217;s seminary. You should probably know that I chose that seminary above all others because I was drawn to John MacArthur&#8217;s fearless preaching of the truth as God revealed it in Scripture. I value the [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is a weird post for me to write. Maybe I should first tell you that I graduated from John MacArthur&#8217;s seminary. You should probably know that I chose that seminary above all others because I was drawn to John MacArthur&#8217;s fearless preaching of the truth as God revealed it in Scripture. I value the education I received at the Master&#8217;s Seminary. </p>



<p>But—oh my gosh—I just heard an audio recording in which John MacArthur demeans and dismisses Beth Moore. I&#8217;m shaking. If I conjure up every ounce of optimism and benefit-of-the-doubt-ness I possess, I still can&#8217;t find a way to describe it as anything other than disdainful and mean-spirited. If I try to give an honest assessment of how it sounds to me, I think I have to say his words sound hateful and anti-Christ.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='696' height='392' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/NeNKHqpBcgc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Here&#8217;s the scenario. John MacArthur is part of a panel discussion, and the moderator asks this: &#8220;I will say a word, and then you need to give a pithy response to that one word.&#8221; The word that MacArthur is asked to comment on? </p>



<p>Beth Moore.</p>



<p>MacArthur&#8217;s response is swift: &#8220;Go home.&#8221; </p>



<p>This was met by cheers and applause the audience. A roomful of people (attending the Truth Matters Conference which is celebrating 50 years of MacArthur&#8217;s ministry) cheered when a PASTOR dismissed a woman made in God&#8217;s image with a demeaning phrase. That word &#8220;pastor&#8221; means &#8220;shepherd.&#8221; This crowd joined a shepherd in collectively dunking on a woman who loves Jesus and loves Scripture and carefully does her best to promote Jesus wherever she goes.</p>



<p>This is absolutely disgusting. I&#8217;m seriously doing the theological equivalent of dry heaving right now. Once more I find myself pleading: <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/05/12/stop-treating-beth-moore-like-garbage/">Stop treating Beth Moore like garbage!</a></p>



<p>MacArthur chose to elaborate a bit: &#8220;There is no case that can be made for a woman preacher. Period. Paragraph. End of discussion.&#8221; </p>



<p>Huge applause. </p>



<p>Except that there is a case that can be made for it, and this case is made by a huge number of scholars and followers of Jesus. MacArthur is allowed to disagree with Beth Moore. Holy smokes. Of course we can disagree about something like this! But he states with absolute confidence and condescension that no one can argue otherwise. And yet I&#8217;ll stand here as a graduate of his seminary, as someone who still employs the hermeneutical tools and methods I learned at his seminary, and make a strong argument to the contrary. So many do. It&#8217;s misleading, harmful, and disgusting to claim that one&#8217;s view on this—regarding which there are between one and a handful passages (depending on which passages one considers relevant) that say anything about this issue. </p>



<p>Phil Johnson, one of MacArthur&#8217;s right hand men, also on the panel, chose to answer the same prompt with the word, &#8220;Narcissistic.&#8221; He said, &#8220;When I first saw her I thought, &#8216;This is what it looks like to preach yourself rather than Christ.'&#8221;</p>



<p>I cannot tell you how disgusting it is to hear someone say this. It&#8217;s so unfair and cruel. It&#8217;s wild to publicly demean a preacher of the gospel who&#8217;s not even in the room. Again, this kind of dismissive attitude and contemptuous statement is anti-Christ. All of the <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/23/the-heresy-of-unity/">many many many</a> calls for love, grace, unity, patience, gracious speech, humility, etc. are thrown out the window. All of the biblical warnings against causing division and controversy are ignored. </p>



<p>MacArthur went on, &#8220;Just because you have the skill to sell jewelry on the TV sales channel doesn&#8217;t mean you should be preaching. There are people who have certain hocking skills. Natural abilities to sell. They have energy and personality and all that. That doesn&#8217;t qualify you to preach.&#8221; </p>



<p>You can tell the  audience doesn&#8217;t know how to respond to that. </p>



<p>And that&#8217;s where I died. Those words are so condescending. They seem calculated to wound. To dishonor. To destroy. When I close my eyes and try to picture Jesus saying words like these, I gag. But these words would be right at home in the mouths of Pharisees. I feel qualified to make that last statement because I personally have Pharisaical tendencies. I&#8217;m constantly tempted to make myself the measure of orthodoxy and to define my preferred crowd as the &#8220;true people of God.&#8221; But I know I&#8217;m wrong in this. That&#8217;s why we started this blog. Jesus is too beautiful and his mission is too important for us <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/01/02/what-is-jackass-theology%ef%bb%bf/">to be jackasses in the name of Jesus</a>.</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;I believe John MacArthur and Phil Johnson need to repent for saying to the hand, &#8216;I have no need of you,&#8217; and to Beth Moore, &#8216;You&#8217;re narcissistic and should either stay at home or sell jewelry on TV.'&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CI+believe+John+MacArthur+and+Phil+Johnson+need+to+repent+for+saying+to+the+hand%2C+%E2%80%98I+have+no+need+of+you%2C%E2%80%99+and+to+Beth+Moore%2C+%E2%80%98You%E2%80%99re+narcissistic+and+should+either+stay+at+home+or+sell+jewelry+on+TV.%27%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-s6" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-s6&t=%E2%80%9CI+believe+John+MacArthur+and+Phil+Johnson+need+to+repent+for+saying+to+the+hand%2C+%E2%80%98I+have+no+need+of+you%2C%E2%80%99+and+to+Beth+Moore%2C+%E2%80%98You%E2%80%99re+narcissistic+and+should+either+stay+at+home+or+sell+jewelry+on+TV.%27%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>I c<a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/25/i-am-don-quixote-but-i-never-think-i-am/">an&#8217;t tell you for sure that my motives are entirely pure</a> in writing this. I&#8217;d like to believe so, and I&#8217;m honestly praying and checking my heart here. If there&#8217;s something I&#8217;m missing about this discussion, I&#8217;d love to hear it. But I believe John MacArthur and Phil Johnson need to repent for saying to the hand, &#8220;I have no need of you,&#8221; and to the foot &#8220;You&#8217;re narcissistic and should either stay at home or sell jewelry on TV.&#8221; I doubt they&#8217;ll read this, and I don&#8217;t expect to be heard favorably if they do, but this breaks my heart, and I&#8217;m confident it breaks the heart of Jesus, who gave his very life to serve and unify his church. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/19/john-macarthurs-disgusting-comment-go-home-beth-moore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>107</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1742</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pastor Kanye &#038; the Problem with Celebrity Conversions</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/17/pastor-kanye-the-problem-with-celebrity-conversions/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/17/pastor-kanye-the-problem-with-celebrity-conversions/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 15:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kanye West]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quentin Tarantino]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1738</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Kanye West has been on a wild ride the last couple years. Most recently, he has been leading Sunday Services, where they basically sing songs to worship God interspersed with Kanye talking a lot about Jesus. He has even said that he will never again make &#8220;secular music.&#8221; Crazy, right? But as you probably know [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kanye West has been on a wild ride the last couple years. Most recently, he has been leading Sunday Services, where they basically sing songs to worship God interspersed with Kanye talking a lot about Jesus. He has even said that he will never again make &#8220;secular music.&#8221; Crazy, right? </p>



<p>But as you probably know (or can at least imagine), no one in the world knows what to make of this. For the gossip media outlets, Kanye&#8217;s just wild and unpredictable and therefore good for business. I sense the average Kanye fan standing back a bit to see what will come of it all. I see some in the Christian community excited about Kanye&#8217;s conversion and the new direction of his music. In my circles at least, I see more Christians skeptical or even derisive about &#8220;Pastor Kanye.&#8221; I personally see things that are really cool about what Kanye&#8217;s up to right now. I have mixed feelings overall: I actually wrote a <a href="https://amzn.to/2IYuIXs">book about the mistaken view of &#8220;secular vs. Christian music&#8221;</a> that Kanye seemed to invoke, but I also love his enthusiasm to use his music for God&#8217;s glory. </p>



<p>Overall, I think this is yet another example of how tricky it is when celebrities convert. Bob Dylan famously became a Christian, and then eventually he leveled out. I have no idea what the implications of any of that are. But I do think we as Christians make this weird for celebrities. On the one hand, we talk as though having a celebrity become a Christian will lead to instant worldwide conversion. On the other hand, everyone policies their every statement and action, looking for reasons why they&#8217;re not a true Christian.</p>



<p>I first thought about this years ago. As I was stepping out of the back room onto the stage to lead the congregation in worship, my buddy said to me, “Don’t freak out, but Pamela Anderson is sitting in the front row.” I said what any worship leader would have said: “Yeah, right.”</p>



<p>I grabbed my guitar and stepped up to the microphone, and there she was, sitting directly in front of me. She seemed fully engaged in the music and the preaching, and as soon as the service ended she slipped out the side door.</p>



<p>This event didn’t have a huge impact on my life, but it made me wonder what church must be like for celebrities. Pamela made it through the service without being hassled, but I did notice that as she rushed out the door one of our pastors went sprinting after her. I’m sure he was just trying to give her a personal connection at the church, but I wonder if that seemed any different to her than the people who swarm her on her way out of other public places. I doubt it.</p>



<p>On another Sunday, I was running the soundboard when Leann Rimes walked in. She arrived early, found a seat in the middle of the Sanctuary, and graciously small-talked with the churchgoers who recognized her. Meanwhile in the sound booth, we whispered like Junior High girls about having a celebrity in front of us. We watched her reactions to the music and the sermon and speculated about the nature of her faith.</p>



<p>We likely agree that joining a community of faith is vital for anyone wanting to follow Jesus. But what would that look like for a major celebrity? Could they really just be part of the church family? We would all agree that celebrities are no better than the rest of us. Most celebrities would affirm this as well. But we don’t really believe it’s true. We get weird. </p>



<p>I once made awkward eye contact with Quentin Tarantino in a Starbucks. As we locked eyes, I saw the soul of a man who was trying hard to blend in, scanning the room to see which one of us would recognize him and call him out for attempting to buy coffee in public like a normal human being. I don’t know what he read in my eyes, but I didn’t out him. Instead, I pretended not to be watching him and walked across the room to discreetly tell a friend, “Don’t look now, but Quentin Tarantino is standing right behind you…”</p>



<p>I can’t imagine how a celebrity maintains normal relationships. Do people actually like me, or are they just trying to get something or look a certain way by hanging out with me? I would think you’d have a ton of acquaintances and very few actual friends. This would be tough in terms of church life.</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;Kanye asked people to give him a little grace if he’s mispronouncing certain phrases: &#8216;I’m a new convert. I recently got saved.&#8217; Maybe we could do that: give him a little grace. Be happy for him.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CKanye+asked+people+to+give+him+a+little+grace%C2%A0if+he%E2%80%99s+mispronouncing+certain+phrases%3A+%E2%80%98I%E2%80%99m+a+new+convert.+I+recently+got+saved.%E2%80%99+Maybe+we+could+do+that%3A+give+him+a+little+grace.+Be+happy+for+him.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-s2" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-s2&t=%E2%80%9CKanye+asked+people+to+give+him+a+little+grace%C2%A0if+he%E2%80%99s+mispronouncing+certain+phrases%3A+%E2%80%98I%E2%80%99m+a+new+convert.+I+recently+got+saved.%E2%80%99+Maybe+we+could+do+that%3A+give+him+a+little+grace.+Be+happy+for+him.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>I don’t have a solution for this, but this should give us more compassion for celebrities who are trying to follow Jesus. We get so disgusted when we hear that “so and so claims to be a Christian but isn’t part of a church.” We are bewildered when a celebrity who seems to love Jesus makes a statement that is theologically off base. You’d be pretty weird too if every person in every church made it difficult for you to connect with the body of Christ.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know what any of this means for Kanye West. My opinion doesn&#8217;t matter at all. But this poor guy seems to be trying to take his first steps at following Jesus and using his enormous platform to draw attention to Jesus. There&#8217;s a pastor who actually attended the same seminary I did that has been pastoring Kanye pretty directly, and <a href="https://www.faithwire.com/2019/10/07/pastor-working-with-kanye-west-reveals-details-of-rappers-radical-salvation-several-months-ago/">he vouches for Kanye&#8217;s faith</a>. I think that&#8217;s pretty cool. At a recent event, <a href="https://relevantmagazine.com/culture/kanye-west-preaching-excuse-me-if-i-miss-pronounce-anything-im-a-recent-convert-i-recently-got-saved/">Kanye asked people to give him a little grace</a> if he&#8217;s mispronouncing certain phrases: &#8220;I&#8217;m a new convert. I recently got saved.&#8221; Maybe we could do that: give him a little grace.</p>



<p>Seems like we should be happy for him. I know I don&#8217;t know better than the pastor who&#8217;s vouching for him. Seems like I can be excited about a lot of what I&#8217;m hearing about the Sunday Services. Also, my trust in Jesus doesn&#8217;t hinge on what Kanye says or does. I&#8217;m confident h<a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/">e doesn&#8217;t need to be policed</a> by the council of evangelical public opinion. I also think it&#8217;s cool he seems to be finding life in Jesus, just as I do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/10/17/pastor-kanye-the-problem-with-celebrity-conversions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1738</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mystery &#038; Humility</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/24/mystery-humility/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/24/mystery-humility/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 05:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denominations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1733</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The great French philosopher of the early 20th century, Étienne Gilson, wrote these words about the world&#8217;s greatest minds trying to make sense of God: &#8220;The divine Being eludes the grasp of our concepts. There is no single idea at our disposal which does not break down in some way when we attempt to apply [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The great French philosopher of the early 20th century, Étienne Gilson, wrote these words about the world&#8217;s greatest minds trying to make sense of God:</p>



<p>&#8220;The divine Being eludes the grasp of our concepts. There is no single idea at our disposal which does not break down in some way when we attempt to apply it to Him. Every denomination is a limitation, but God is above all limitation, and therefore above all denomination no matter how exalted it may be&#8221; (<em>Spirit of Mediaeval Philosophy</em>, 1936, 56.).</p>



<p>His statement is not at all controversial. God &#8220;eludes the grasp of our concepts.&#8221; Do any of us really believe we know everything about God? Do we believe any of our categories or concepts are sufficient? There is so much mystery in play anytime human beings speak or even think about God.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll all acknowledge this. But in my experience, our acknowledgement of the mystery of God does not usually come with the humility that ought to accompany such an acknowledgement. </p>



<p>If God is indeed mysterious, then why are we not more humble about our limited perspectives?</p>



<p>Gilson says that every denomination is a limitation. Isn&#8217;t that so? Denominations are not inherently bad. But <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/06/10/sectual-sin/">they are inherently limited</a>. At the heart of every denomination is the insistence that God is like this, not like that. Differentiation is good, categorization is helpful, and absolute truth exists. To be human is to be limited. To form a denomination is to embrace specific limitations. This is not the problem. The problem is our tendency to take the box we draw around our denomination or camp or position and then insist that the box accurately represents God is his fullness.</p>



<p>There is mystery when we talk about God! Does this not require us to be humble in our statements about God? Should we not acknowledge the limitations of our perspectives? Should we not be open to hearing others speak about God in ways that sound foreign to us?</p>



<p>Many of our denominations are good. None of them is sufficient.</p>



<p>Think of the people who are part of your church. You worship and serve regularly with people who hold a variety of views about who God is and what he does. God is bigger than what any one of you thinks about him.</p>



<p>But what about the person in your church with whom you have firm theological disagreements? Or the person in the other church or denomination whose theology you can&#8217;t accept? Is it true that &#8220;there is no single idea at our disposal which does not break down in some way when we attempt to apply it to God?&#8221; I&#8217;m not suggesting we treat wrong as right. I don&#8217;t endorse going against God&#8217;s revelation of himself in Scripture. I&#8217;m suggesting that our understanding of God is limited, and that perhaps we should view each other in this light.</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;There is no single idea at our disposal which does not break down in some way when we attempt to apply it to God.&#8221; &#8211; Étienne Gilson<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CThere+is+no+single+idea+at+our+disposal+which+does+not+break+down+in+some+way+when+we+attempt+to+apply+it+to+God.%E2%80%9D+%E2%80%93+%C3%89tienne+Gilson&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rX" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rX&t=%E2%80%9CThere+is+no+single+idea+at+our+disposal+which+does+not+break+down+in+some+way+when+we+attempt+to+apply+it+to+God.%E2%80%9D+%E2%80%93+%C3%89tienne+Gilson" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>Gilson goes on to say that &#8220;the only adequate expression of God would be God.&#8221; I love that. Anytime we break down some part of God and try to explain him, we&#8217;re inherently mistaken—not necessarily through inaccuracy, but through incompletion. </p>



<p>Flannery O&#8217;Connor said this about writing fiction: “Some people have the notion that you read the story and then climb out of it into the meaning, but for the fiction writer himself the whole story is the meaning, because it is an experience, not an abstraction” (Mystery &amp; Manners, 73). She quotes John Peale Bishop: &#8220;You can’t say Cezanne painted apples and a tablecloth and have said what Cezanne painted.&#8221;  </p>



<p>In other words, we have a tendency to want to summarize art, but it doesn&#8217;t work like that. She says: &#8220;A story is a way to say something that can’t be said any other way, and it takes every word in the story to say what the meaning is. You tell a story because a statement would be inadequate. When anybody asks what a story is about, the only proper thing is to tell him to read the story. The meaning of fiction is not abstract meaning but experienced meaning, and the purpose of making a statement about the meaning of a story is only to help you to experience that meaning more fully” (96).</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">When speaking about God &#8220;our poor human words express only a part of that which has no parts.&#8221; &#8211; Étienne Gilson<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=When+speaking+about+God+%E2%80%9Cour+poor+human+words+express+only+a+part+of+that+which+has+no+parts.%E2%80%9D+%E2%80%93+%C3%89tienne+Gilson&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rX" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rX&t=When+speaking+about+God+%E2%80%9Cour+poor+human+words+express+only+a+part+of+that+which+has+no+parts.%E2%80%9D+%E2%80%93+%C3%89tienne+Gilson" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>What Flannery O&#8217;Connor says about art also (mysteriously) applies to God. As Gilson says, when speaking about God &#8220;our poor human words express only a part of that which has no parts.&#8221; This is okay, because this is the way God has designed it. What&#8217;s not okay, however, is when we discard the humility that necessarily accompanies mystery. When we do this, we&#8217;re not being theological, or helpful, or godly, or biblical, or faithful. <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/01/02/what-is-jackass-theology%ef%bb%bf/">We&#8217;re being jackasses</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/24/mystery-humility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1733</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Benny Hinn Changed: Do We Celebrate or Scoff?</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/11/benny-hinn-changed-do-we-celebrate-or-scoff/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/11/benny-hinn-changed-do-we-celebrate-or-scoff/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Francis Chan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1726</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[What was your first reaction to the news that Benny Hinn changed his theology regarding the prosperity gospel? If you need a little context, there is a video in which Hinn denounces the teaching that made him famous: that if we have enough faith (and give enough money), we can gain health, wealth, and prosperity. [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>What was your first reaction to the news that Benny Hinn changed his theology regarding the prosperity gospel? If you need a little context, there is a video in which Hinn denounces the teaching that made him famous: that if we have enough faith (and give enough money), we can gain health, wealth, and prosperity. </p>



<p>In the video, Hinn acknowledged that in many circles all you hear is a <em>&#8220;feel good message&#8221;</em> about <em>&#8220;how to build the flesh.&#8221;</em> He said, <em>“I’m sorry to say that prosperity has gone a little crazy, and I’m correcting my own theology. And you need to all know it. Because when I read the Bible now, I don’t see it in the same eyes I saw the Bible 20 years ago.”</em></p>



<p>Anyone familiar with Benny Hinn and his reputation will be shocked by that news. It&#8217;s something we never thought we&#8217;d hear. But you can watch the video. He says it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='696' height='392' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/4TQQirZI9Eo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>A friend asked him if he was ready to make this shift public, and Hinn said, <em>“Well, not totally. Because I don’t want to hurt my friends, whom I love, who believe things I don’t believe anymore.” </em></p>



<p>To me, that’s understandable. Many of us are under enormous pressure <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/">to stay in line</a> with our theological camps. This is true in my experience as a pastor, and I can imagine it must be 1,000 times more true for pastors who are well known. As a matter of fact, <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/15/farewell-francis-chan/">Francis Chan recently got raked over the coals</a> by some in his own camp because they were SUSPICIOUS that he might be inwardly endorsing the theology of Benny Hinn, despite his explicit and repeated words to the contrary. I actually want to say more about that episode in a minute because of its obvious relevance here, but let that stand for a moment. There is tremendous pressure to never betray your camp or never even to be perceived as doing so. <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/15/farewell-francis-chan/">Take a picture in the wrong place</a> or <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/05/12/stop-treating-beth-moore-like-garbage/">preach to the wrong audience</a> and receive your &#8220;<a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/15/farewell-francis-chan/">Farewell</a>!&#8221; So Hinn’s words here resonate with me. I can see why he didn’t want to say anything. </p>



<p>AND YET, HE DID! He knew it would be hard, but he felt compelled by the force of the truth and decided he had to speak against a theological system he had previously endorsed. A system that had made him famous and successful. I respect that. </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the substance of it: <em>“I will tell you something now that’s going to shock you. I think it’s an offense to the Lord, it’s an offense to say ‘Give $1,000.&#8217; I think it’s an offense to the Holy Spirit to place a price on the gospel. I’m done with it…I think that hurts the gospel…If I hear one more time ‘Break the back of poverty with $1,000,&#8217; I’m going to rebuke them. I think that’s buying the gospel, that’s buying the blessing, that’s grieving the Holy Spirit…If you’re not giving because you love Jesus, don’t bother giving. I think giving has become such a gimmick it’s making me sick to my stomach. And I’ve been sick for a while, too; I just couldn’t say it. And now the lid is off. I’ve had it. Do you know why? I don’t want to get to heaven and be rebuked. I think it’s time we say it like it is: the gospel is not for sale. And the blessings of God are not for sale. And miracles are not for sale. And prosperity is not for sale.”</em></p>



<p>It&#8217;s a surreal experience for me to hear Benny Hinn utter these words. And I&#8217;ll be honest, my first reaction was not joy. I was skeptical. I sat there thinking, &#8220;Okay, sure. We&#8217;ll see how this goes.&#8221; </p>



<p>Why?</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s what my response should have been. I should have spent the last few decades praying for Benny Hinn. Asking God to give him a clear understanding of Scripture and a heart that burns with love for Jesus. I don&#8217;t think I was wrong to disagree with his theology. I think it&#8217;s likely the indignation I felt was righteous when I saw him doing what I took to be selling the gospel for personal gain. I still feel that way about the prosperity gospel. Actually, I now agree with Benny Hinn: I think it&#8217;s an offense to the Lord to place a price on the gospel. But I should have been praying for his wellbeing and the wellbeing of his followers, which would undoubtedly include a correction in his theology. I don&#8217;t recall doing this once.</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;Benny Hinn has renounced the prosperity gospel. I&#8217;d be a jackass to refuse to celebrate with him. I want to celebrate that God seems to have done something I didn&#8217;t think he would.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CBenny+Hinn+has+renounced+the+prosperity+gospel.+I%E2%80%99d+be+a+jackass+to+refuse+to+celebrate+with+him.+I+want+to+celebrate+that+God+seems+to+have+done+something+I+didn%E2%80%99t+think+he+would.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rQ" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rQ&t=%E2%80%9CBenny+Hinn+has+renounced+the+prosperity+gospel.+I%E2%80%99d+be+a+jackass+to+refuse+to+celebrate+with+him.+I+want+to+celebrate+that+God+seems+to+have+done+something+I+didn%E2%80%99t+think+he+would.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>But now that I was watching the miracle I should have been praying for, with Benny Hinn publicly correctly his theology and denouncing the prosperity gospel, I wasn&#8217;t celebrating. I wasn&#8217;t thanking the Lord. My initial reaction was skepticism, mocking, and criticism. I&#8217;ve seen a couple responses like this online: He can say whatever he wants, that&#8217;s not true repentance. We&#8217;ll see what happens from here. Etc. </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the thing: I doubt Benny Hinn now has perfect theology. I know I don&#8217;t. He won&#8217;t do everything perfect from here. I definitely won&#8217;t. And maybe it&#8217;s all a sham and he&#8217;s just trying to get attention or something. It&#8217;s possible, but I&#8217;d be a <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/01/02/what-is-jackass-theology%ef%bb%bf/">jackass</a> to refuse to celebrate with and for him at this point. My initial response was full of jackassery. I&#8217;m sorry for that. I want to celebrate that God seems to have done something I didn&#8217;t think he would. Praise God for Benny Hinn!</p>



<p>And back to Francis Chan for a quick minute. <a href="https://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/15/farewell-francis-chan/">He was &#8220;farewelled&#8221; for taking a selfie with Benny Hinn</a>. Apparently he was supposed to stay the hell away and only say mean things to Hinn. I don&#8217;t know that Francis Chan had any role in Benny Hinn&#8217;s realization.  But I know that Francis decided not to treat him as a complete enemy and curse him. Francis apparently treated him with love. Now that Benny Hinn is on a new path, Francis&#8217; decision seems like a good one. Are we willing to acknowledge this? Or do the farewell Francisers simply move on as if they did everything perfect? I know what my assumptions are on that one, but I also know that these assumptions come from my inner jackass. I&#8217;m trying to let go of those impulses and simply celebrate what I see God doing. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/11/benny-hinn-changed-do-we-celebrate-or-scoff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1726</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>If We Cared More, We&#8217;d Fight Less</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Francis Schaeffer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soren Kierkegaard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1722</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[You might think we fight so much because we all care too much. But I&#8217;m convinced it&#8217;s the opposite. And it&#8217;s a Kierkegaard quote that makes me think this. In one of his journals, he wrote: &#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>You might think we fight so much because we all care too much. But I&#8217;m convinced it&#8217;s the opposite. And it&#8217;s a Kierkegaard quote that makes me think this. In one of his journals, he wrote:</p>



<p>&#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must know… It is a question of understanding my destiny, of seeing what God really wants me to do; the thing is to find a truth which is for me, to find the idea for which I am willing to live and die. And what use here would it be if I were to discover a so-called objective truth, or if I worked my way through the philosophers&#8217; systems and were able to call them all to account on request, point out inconsistencies in every single circle? …What use would it be if truth were to stand there before me, cold and naked, not caring whether I acknowledged it or not, and inducing an anxious shudder rather than trusting devotion? Certainly I won&#8217;t deny that I still accept an imperative of knowledge and that one can also be influenced by it, but then it must be taken up alive in me, and this is what I now see as the main point. It is this my soul thirsts for as the African deserts thirst for water.&#8221;</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">Kierkegaard: &#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must know…to find a truth which is for me, to find the idea for which I am willing to live and die.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Kierkegaard%3A+%E2%80%9CWhat+I+really+need+is+to+be+clear+about+what+I+am+to+do%2C+not+about+what+I+must+know%E2%80%A6to+find+a+truth+which+is+for+me%2C+to+find+the+idea+for+which+I+am+willing+to+live+and+die.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM&t=Kierkegaard%3A+%E2%80%9CWhat+I+really+need+is+to+be+clear+about+what+I+am+to+do%2C+not+about+what+I+must+know%E2%80%A6to+find+a+truth+which+is+for+me%2C+to+find+the+idea+for+which+I+am+willing+to+live+and+die.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>Kierkegaard makes me wonder if a major problem in our discourteous theological debates is that we don&#8217;t care enough. Maybe that sounds crazy. Our debates seem passionate. The level of disagreement and our unwillingness to budge or consider where someone else is coming from seem to be symptoms of caring too much. But I wonder…</p>



<p>Maybe our problem is that we treat the truth as a thing that &#8220;stands there before us, cold and naked.&#8221; In this paradigm, the truth is something purely external, something set off to the side. It can be seen, acknowledged, assented to, but it&#8217;s not within us, doing the difficult work of transforming us. If the truth is like a list of rules printed out and displayed on a wall, then it can be applied and wielded legalistically. Weaponistically. In this model, we look at the truth externally as we sit around referencing &#8220;common sense&#8221; and criticizing everyone because &#8220;only an idiot could see things differently.&#8221;</p>



<p>Here is precisely where Kierkegaard&#8217;s pursuit could help us so much. Because truth is not meant merely to produce an &#8220;anxious shudder&#8221; within us. It&#8217;s meant to produce &#8220;trusting devotion.&#8221; It&#8217;s not about finding the cold, dead list of words that we will judge everyone by. It&#8217;s about finding a truth that so shapes our internal lives that it is true objectively, and also subjectively. It is true in reality, but—significantly—it is also true FOR ME. That&#8217;s not relativism, that&#8217;s heart-appropriated, deep-seated ownership of the truth. It&#8217;s the refusal to be a &#8220;hearer of the Word&#8221; only, but rather a &#8220;doer of the Word&#8221; (see James 1:22). </p>



<p>What if we stopped policing comments and diving into debates over matters where the truth has not so purchased our souls that we are being shaped by it at the deepest level? What if we disciplined ourselves to <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/05/20/have-fewer-opinions/">have fewer opinions</a> and instead threw ourselves into growing more passionate for the realities of Jesus and his gospel? </p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;I suspect that much of the vitriol we spew and encounter over theological debates comes from a deep-seated insecurity.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CI+suspect+that+much+of+the+vitriol+we+spew+and+encounter+over+theological+debates+comes+from+a+deep-seated+insecurity.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM&t=%E2%80%9CI+suspect+that+much+of+the+vitriol+we+spew+and+encounter+over+theological+debates+comes+from+a+deep-seated+insecurity.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>I honestly think this would change the Church. I suspect that much of the vitriol we spew and encounter over theological debates comes from a deep-seated insecurity. We&#8217;re not confident in our view of the truth, we&#8217;re worried that someone else is going to see things differently or devalue our perspective, so we lash out because we&#8217;re afraid a simple explanation of our beliefs won&#8217;t be enough. But so what if it&#8217;s not enough? Why do we need everyone to agree with us? The answer is that we don&#8217;t. If the truth matters so much to us in a certain area that it has changed and is changing us, we can share that truth winsomely without the desperation and aggression that characterizes the fearful.</p>



<p>I have always loved a certain line in Francis Schaeffer&#8217;s book <em><a href="https://amzn.to/2NLWHNz">Art and the Bible</a>.</em> After detailing the biblical case for making art that doesn&#8217;t need to be overtly religious, he says  &#8220;When you begin to understand this sort of thing, suddenly you can begin to breathe, and all the terrible pressure that has been put on us by making art something less than spiritual suddenly begins to disappear. And with this truth comes beauty and with this beauty a freedom before God.&#8221; He&#8217;s talking to artists, but I think it fits here as well. When we begin to see the ways a certain truth is true not just in general, but specifically in me, then there comes the freedom of confidence and security. </p>



<p>We need to start caring more so we can start fighting less. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1722</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Heresy of Unity</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/23/the-heresy-of-unity/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/23/the-heresy-of-unity/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 15:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beth Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conservatives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1714</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a danger in the Church today where people claim to be speaking for God, but they are either embarrassed or afraid of speaking God&#8217;s truth clearly, so they water it down. Changing God&#8217;s Word to fit our own agendas and desires is called heresy. We have no right to come before God, decide that [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There&#8217;s a danger in the Church today where people claim to be speaking for God, but they are either embarrassed or afraid of speaking God&#8217;s truth clearly, so they water it down. Changing God&#8217;s Word to fit our own agendas and desires is called heresy. We have no right to come before God, decide that we don&#8217;t like some of the things he says, and then water things down so we and the people we&#8217;re speaking to can feel better about themselves. If God says something, we have to believe that he&#8217;s right. It shouldn&#8217;t be difficult to accept that he knows more than we do. When I disagree with something God says, I have to assume he&#8217;s right and that life will be better for me if I embrace his truth rather than trying to create my own.</p>



<p><strong>In case it isn&#8217;t clear at this point, I&#8217;m speaking about those people who lift their pet doctrines and self-made theological boundary lines higher than the commands Jesus clearly identified as the most important: to love God and to love our neighbors.</strong></p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the irony that Ryan and I have found as we&#8217;ve tried to expose Jackass Theology. The more we try to speak clearly and boldly in the ways Jesus spoke clearly and boldly, the more we&#8217;ve been criticized for watering down Scripture. We&#8217;ve been dismissed as &#8220;liberal&#8221; and &#8220;<a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/07/09/stop-equating-peacemaking-with-compromising/">compromisers</a>&#8221; when we have said that the command to love and not slander someone like <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/06/03/beth-moore-vs-the-sbc/">Beth Moore</a> is more clearly emphasized in Scripture than statements about how women are to serve in ministry. We&#8217;ve been portrayed as spineless because we’ve said that God values love, joy, and peace. </p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the thing. I believe in being biblical. I went to an extremely conservative seminary where we learned to take Scripture at face value. I learned to interpret Scripture literally at almost every turn. That&#8217;s still my default: if the literal sense makes sense, seek no other sense. </p>



<p>But here&#8217;s what I&#8217;m finding: conservatives will call you &#8220;biblical&#8221; if you follow a literal view of hell or the millennium or homosexuality. But so many conservatives get upset if you take a literal interpretation of:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;Live in harmony with one another&#8221; &#8211; Rom. 12:16</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;If possible, so far as it depends on you, live peaceably with all.&#8221; &#8211; Rom. 12:18</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;Charge them before God not to quarrel about words, which does no good, but only ruins the hearers.&#8221; &#8211; 2 Tim. 2:14</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;Have nothing to do with foolish, ignorant controversies; you know that they breed quarrels. And the Lord’s servant must not be quarrelsome but kind to everyone, able to teach, patiently enduring evil, correcting his opponents with gentleness.&#8221; &#8211; 2 Tim. 2:23–25</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;The works of the flesh are evident: sexual immorality, impurity, sensuality, idolatry, sorcery, <strong>enmity, strife, jealousy, fits of anger, rivalries, dissensions, divisions</strong>, envy, drunkenness, orgies, and things like these.&#8221; &#8211; Gal. 5:19–21</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;And since they did not see fit to acknowledge God, God gave them up to a debased mind to do what ought not to be done. They were filled with all manner of unrighteousness, evil, covetousness, malice. They are full of envy, murder, <strong>strife, deceit, maliciousness. They are gossips, slanderers, haters of God, insolent, haughty, boastful, inventors of evil,</strong> disobedient to parents, foolish, faithless, <strong>heartless, ruthless.</strong> Though they know God’s righteous decree that those who practice such things deserve to die, they not only do them but give approval to those who practice them.&#8221; &#8211; Rom. 1:28–32</p></blockquote>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;If I take a statement about sexual behavior literally, I&#8217;m called conservative and biblical. If I take a biblical statement about avoiding disunity literally, I&#8217;m called a liberal, soft, cowardly, and compromising.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CIf+I+take+a+statement+about+sexual+behavior+literally%2C+I%E2%80%99m+called+conservative+and+biblical.+If+I+take+a+biblical+statement+about+avoiding+disunity+literally%2C+I%E2%80%99m+called+a+liberal%2C+soft%2C+cowardly%2C+and+compromising.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rE" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rE&t=%E2%80%9CIf+I+take+a+statement+about+sexual+behavior+literally%2C+I%E2%80%99m+called+conservative+and+biblical.+If+I+take+a+biblical+statement+about+avoiding+disunity+literally%2C+I%E2%80%99m+called+a+liberal%2C+soft%2C+cowardly%2C+and+compromising.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>These passages are the very tiny tip of the very large iceberg of the consistent New Testament teaching against disunity, slander, division, and quarreling. There are certainly commands to avoid false doctrine and instructions to correct those who teach something other than God&#8217;s truth. We need to take those seriously. But here&#8217;s what I&#8217;m having a hard time getting across: There are many commands to love others, to be united with others, to avoid quarreling and division, and to promote peace. These commands are also in the Bible, and they need to be taken seriously. Literally, even. </p>



<p>And here&#8217;s the problem I&#8217;m encountering: If I take a biblical statement about sexual behavior literally, I&#8217;m called a conservative and my stance is considered &#8220;biblical.&#8221; If I take a biblical statement about avoiding disunity literally, I&#8217;m called a liberal and my stance is considered soft and cowardly and compromising. </p>



<p>That&#8217;s wrong. We all have to make choices about which parts of the Bible are meant to be taken literally. All of us. I can&#8217;t tell you every passage that is meant to be taken purely literally (Selling all of your possessions? Plucking out your eye? Wearing head coverings?). But I can tell you that I&#8217;m extremely confident that Jesus&#8217; commands to love and be unified and to avoid controversy are meant to be taken literally. You&#8217;re free to interpret those passages figuratively or to decide that Jesus didn&#8217;t really mean what he said in those places. But if you make that choice, please acknowledge that I&#8217;m the one who is  interpreting the Bible literally when I fight for unity in the church rather than dividing over every man-made boundary. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/23/the-heresy-of-unity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1714</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Becket Cook: WWJD LGBT?</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/15/becket-cook-wwjd-lgbt/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/15/becket-cook-wwjd-lgbt/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 14:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Becket Cook]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Table]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A Change of Affection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1700</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The following is a guest post from Becket Cook, a friend of ours, a Hollywood set designer, and the author of A Change of Affection: A Gay Man&#8217;s Incredible Story of Redemption. On Sunday, September 20, 2009, I walked into an evangelical church in Hollywood called Reality LA as a self-proclaimed atheist and a gay [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>The following is a guest post from Becket Cook, a friend of ours, a Hollywood set designer, and the author of</em> <a href="https://amzn.to/31CQ83q">A Change of Affection: A Gay Man&#8217;s Incredible Story of Redemption</a>. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>On Sunday, September 20, 2009, I walked into an evangelical church in Hollywood called Reality LA as a self-proclaimed atheist and a gay man; two hours later I walked out a born-again Christian who no longer identified as gay. The power of the gospel utterly transformed me during that service. I now live as a single, celibate man. </p>



<p>It wasn&#8217;t condemning guilt heaped on me by Christians that spurred the transformation. It was the power of God. I am happy to deny myself and take up my cross and follow Jesus, because He’s infinitely worth it!</p>



<p>Let’s start by asking the obvious question: What would Jesus do with regards to those in the LGBT community? Would He distance himself from them? Would He refuse to interact with them? Would He look at them as a lost cause and move on? Would He protest gay pride parades? Would He hold up signs with condemning slogans scrawled across them? Would He reject them?</p>



<p>Quite the opposite.</p>



<p>In the Synoptic Gospels, we see Jesus dining with “sinners and tax collectors.” This was incredibly counter-cultural. Instead of acting like the religious folks of His day, He deigned to dine with “those people.” This unexpected action mortified and mystified the religious class. They were downright indignant. In His typical fashion, Jesus schools them:</p>



<p><em>I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.</em> — Mark 2:17<br>
Jesus focused on individuals, not groups (the story of the Samaritan woman at the well, for example). He was after people’s hearts, hence His deeply personal approach to those whom He encountered.</p>



<p>Of course, Jesus never compromised the truth: <em>Unless you repent, you will all likewise perish.</em> — Luke 13:3 </p>



<p>But Jesus was the master of balancing grace with truth. He does this perfectly throughout the Gospels.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img src="https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?fit=683%2C1024" alt="" class="wp-image-1701" width="199" height="298" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?w=750 750w, https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?resize=200%2C300 200w, https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?resize=683%2C1024 683w, https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?resize=696%2C1044 696w, https://i1.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/64-Becket-Cook-2.jpg?resize=280%2C420 280w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></figure></div>



<p>My sister-in-law, Kim, was a natural at this. For me, she was a great example of how a Christian should respond to this issue. She has been a strong believer since early in her childhood. I met her when I was in high school, and she started dating my older brother, Greg. She and I always had a special bond; we enjoyed chatting and hanging out with each other. Years later, after I came out as gay to my whole family, my relationship with Kim remained the same, even though she was what I would have called a Bible-thumping, evangelical Christian. I knew that she knew that I knew that she believed homosexuality was a sin, but I never felt an ounce of condemnation from her. She never sat me down to explain to me that I was sinning. She never quoted Bible verses to me. She never judged me for my lifestyle. Instead, she did something far more dangerous: she prayed…for twenty years!</p>



<p>Over the years, while living in Los Angeles, I would go back to Dallas (my hometown) for Christmas. One of the highlights of my visits was getting together with Kim at the nearest coffee shop. We would chat for hours. I would talk about guys; she would talk about God. She was genuinely interested in my life, and never once said to me, “You know, you’re still sinning.” She was very open about her faith and would talk about what God was doing in her life. But this didn’t bother me, because I sensed an unconditional love from her. Her love for me didn’t increase or decrease based on whether or not I was in a relationship with a guy at that particular moment. In other words, she didn’t withhold love from me because of the way I lived my life.</p>



<p>She did two key things throughout the years: she loved me unconditionally and prayed for me without ceasing. That’s it. And it worked!</p>



<p>I was recently invited to a small dinner party at an incredibly beautiful home in Malibu. A friend from church was a work colleague with the owner, who was a gay man. Much to my friend’s and my surprise, the owner wanted to hear more about Christianity. He was curious as to why two gay guys would give up that life to follow Christ. Of course, we were more than happy to have this opportunity to share the Gospel with this group of relatively hardened skeptics, both gay and straight. The only problem was that our gracious host had failed to mention to his friends that two evangelical Christians, who had both been saved out of the homosexual life, were the guests of honor!</p>



<p>When, immediately after the first course was served, our host turned to me and asked if I would share my story with everyone at the table, I almost choked on my fennel salad. But as I was detailing the story of my conversion, I saw a look of genuine interest on the faces of the listeners; that is, until one of them asked the $64,000 question: “What about your sexuality?” As I addressed that issue, there was a sudden shift in the room. The mood quickly changed from polite interest to semi-hostile disgust. I tried my best to explain why homosexual behavior was incompatible with Christianity, when suddenly the discussion at the table became very animated. Various guests were chiming in with their own views, not only on this incendiary subject but on “spirituality” in general. </p>



<p>After our second course, the conversation started to become heated. So much so that at one point, when I felt like it was getting out of hand, I stopped everyone and said: “Guys, guys. I just want you all to know that the only reason I drove an hour out to Malibu on a school night during midterms (I was in seminary at the time) is because I love you! That’s it. I’m not here to win an argument. I’m here because I love you. Period.” Everyone was taken aback by this unexpected expression of my motives. A few of them seemed dumbstruck. The temperature in the room instantly dropped, bonhomie was quickly restored, and the evening ended on a good note. We didn’t experience a mass conversion that evening, but I was thankful for the opportunity to share what God has done in my life. Seeds were planted.</p>



<p>According to Jesus, the second greatest commandment is to love our neighbor as ourselves.</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;Love people without condemning. Billy Graham famously said, &#8216;It is the Holy Spirit’s job to convict, God’s job to judge, and my job to love.&#8217; This could make all the difference in the world.”<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CLove+people+without+condemning.+Billy+Graham+famously+said%2C+%E2%80%98It+is+the+Holy+Spirit%E2%80%99s+job+to+convict%2C+God%E2%80%99s+job+to+judge%2C+and+my+job+to+love.%E2%80%99+This+could+make+all+the+difference+in+the+world.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rq" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rq&t=%E2%80%9CLove+people+without+condemning.+Billy+Graham+famously+said%2C+%E2%80%98It+is+the+Holy+Spirit%E2%80%99s+job+to+convict%2C+God%E2%80%99s+job+to+judge%2C+and+my+job+to+love.%E2%80%99+This+could+make+all+the+difference+in+the+world.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>We know what happened when the lawyer was foolish enough to put Jesus to the test by asking who his neighbor was. After telling the Parable of the Good Samaritan, Jesus asks the lawyer which man in the parable proved to be a neighbor to the man who fell among robbers. The lawyer responds,</p>



<p><em>The one who showed him mercy.</em></p>



<p>Jesus told him to go and do likewise (Luke 10:25-37).</p>



<p>Let us also do likewise. Get a coffee or share a meal with a gay family member or friend. Love him or her without condemning. This could make all the difference in the world. I think Billy Graham put it best when he famously said, “It is the Holy Spirit’s job to convict, God’s job to judge, and my job to love.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>A Word from Jackass Theology</strong><br>
We, Ryan and Mark, appreciate Becket and his story so much. God has carried him through a lot, and when the time was perfect, God got Becket&#8217;s attention and grabbed his heart. While we know there are severe disagreements regarding issues related to the LGBT community, Becket&#8217;s story is a great example of God&#8217;s love traveling through loving relationships. </p>



<p>We highly recommend Becket&#8217;s new memoir. It&#8217;s an incredible story, and he challenges all of us—gay or straight–to give ourselves fully to Jesus. </p>



<p>In an effort to stand firm on God&#8217;s truth, we have joined many other Christians in treating beautiful people made in God&#8217;s image like jackasses. This is yet another area where we have had to <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/01/02/what-is-jackass-theology%ef%bb%bf/">confess our jackassery</a> and ask, as Becket does, What Would Jesus Do? On the other hand, Becket has also taken a lot heat regarding his book because he now holds a non-affirming stance. All of this is Becket&#8217;s story, he&#8217;s sharing what happened to him and the convictions he developed. Jackassery can flow in both directions; we all need to relate to one another in love. Becket&#8217;s story is a reminder that we don&#8217;t have to drop our convictions to love and value another person. Remember that Jesus said the world would know that we are his disciples by our love (John 13:35), not by our impeccable moral standards or firmly articulated convictions. </p>


<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1400212308/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=li2&amp;tag=jackasstheolo-20&amp;linkId=aafb40997f774fe83caa29b6553170e1&amp;language=en_US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=1400212308&amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=jackasstheolo-20&amp;language=en_US"></a><img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=jackasstheolo-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1400212308" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;"></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/15/becket-cook-wwjd-lgbt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1700</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kierkegaard: Love Believes All Things</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/06/love-believes-all-things/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/06/love-believes-all-things/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 15:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soren Kierkegaard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1691</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In his brilliant book Works of Love, Søren Kierkegaard lays out a concept that would absolutely revolutionize our lives, our churches, and our society. It&#8217;s simple, but the impact would be profound. And it&#8217;s simply this: LOVE BELIEVES ALL THINGS That&#8217;s it, just a phrase from 1 Corinthians 13:7. But if we actually took it [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In his brilliant book <em><a href="https://amzn.to/2YMs6kw">Works of Love</a></em>, Søren Kierkegaard lays out a concept that would absolutely revolutionize our lives, our churches, and our society. It&#8217;s simple, but the impact would be profound. And it&#8217;s simply this:</p>



<p>LOVE BELIEVES ALL THINGS</p>



<p>That&#8217;s it, just a phrase from 1 Corinthians 13:7. But if we actually took it seriously, life would never be the same.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s common for us to be afraid of getting someone wrong. We hesitate with our love. It takes us a while to warm up to someone, we try not to really invest in a person until we know they&#8217;re not going to let us down. I know this reality very well. I&#8217;m pretty gregarious in general, but I&#8217;m suspicious of a lot of people. I&#8217;m afraid to think too highly of a person until I have a reason to raise my view of him or her. </p>



<p>Kierkegaard affirms that we&#8217;re right to be afraid of getting someone wrong, but he says we&#8217;re fearful in the wrong direction. We shouldn&#8217;t be afraid of thinking too highly of a person. We should be terrified of thinking too little of them. If you think too highly of a person and treat them well, then you find out they&#8217;re actually a jerk, then you&#8217;re likely to get hurt. But if you think too little of someone, then find out they&#8217;re an amazing, loving person—what then? You&#8217;ve sidelined someone unnecessarily. You&#8217;ve limited their potential. You&#8217;ve robbed yourself of an opportunity and you&#8217;ve diminished that person. </p>



<p>Maybe you&#8217;re not convinced yet. If this doesn&#8217;t sound right to you, it&#8217;s probably because you, like me, have a jacked up view of love.</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;We should be more afraid of thinking too little than of thinking too highly of a person. If I think too highly of them I might get hurt. If I think too little of them, I demean their humanity and am not loving.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CWe+should+be+more+afraid+of+thinking+too+little+than+of+thinking+too+highly+of+a+person.+If+I+think+too+highly+of+them+I+might+get+hurt.+If+I+think+too+little+of+them%2C+I+demean+their+humanity+and+am+not+loving.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rh" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rh&t=%E2%80%9CWe+should+be+more+afraid+of+thinking+too+little+than+of+thinking+too+highly+of+a+person.+If+I+think+too+highly+of+them+I+might+get+hurt.+If+I+think+too+little+of+them%2C+I+demean+their+humanity+and+am+not+loving.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>Kierkegaard urges us to see it like this: It&#8217;s impossible for someone to steal something you&#8217;re trying to gift to them. If you&#8217;re trying to put money in someone&#8217;s pocket, and that person grabs the money and walks away with it, have you been robbed? They may feel like they&#8217;re making off with your money, but you&#8217;ve accomplished your purpose. You wanted to give them something, and they took it. </p>



<p>This is not how we tend to think about love. </p>



<p>We often love because we want to be loved in return. When we love someone and that love is not reciprocated, we feel like it was a waste, or that we&#8217;ve been taken advantage of, or that we made a mistake. But for Kierkegaard, love is something we owe to the people around us (Rom. 13:8). It&#8217;s something we are called to give at every opportunity, and the goal of love is blessing the neighbor standing before us, not receiving back what is being given away. </p>



<p>So if you love someone, and they take your love and only hurt you in return, has your love not done what it set out to do? You can&#8217;t be robbed if you&#8217;re trying to give it away. You can only be duped in loving someone if you were expecting something in return. </p>



<p>This is easy enough to do with the people we are naturally inclined to love. Kierkegaard calls this preferential love, and at its worst, it&#8217;s just a form of self-love (meaning that we&#8217;re doing it for the benefit we receive). It&#8217;s much more difficult to love a stranger or enemy without expecting anything in return. But is this not Jesus&#8217; message in the parable of the Good Samaritan? Don&#8217;t forget that Jesus told this parable in response to the question: &#8220;And who is my neighbor?&#8221; And don&#8217;t forget that would-be Jesus-followers asked him THAT question in response to his command to &#8220;love your neighbor as yourself.&#8221;</p>



<p>If your goal is to love the person who stands before you, then you won&#8217;t stop loving them because they mistreat you in return. </p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;Love does not assume the worst. It simply believes that each person is worthy of love. It believes that each person is capable of love. It&#8217;s not afraid of being duped, because its only goal is to give itself away.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CLove+does+not+assume+the+worst.+It+simply+believes+that+each+person+is+worthy+of+love.+It+believes+that+each+person+is+capable+of+love.+It%E2%80%99s+not+afraid+of+being+duped%2C+because+its+only+goal+is+to+give+itself+away.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rh" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rh&t=%E2%80%9CLove+does+not+assume+the+worst.+It+simply+believes+that+each+person+is+worthy+of+love.+It+believes+that+each+person+is+capable+of+love.+It%E2%80%99s+not+afraid+of+being+duped%2C+because+its+only+goal+is+to+give+itself+away.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>That&#8217;s powerful. And it would change everything. Think of that in terms of the people living in your own house. But don&#8217;t stop there. Think of in terms of the people living on your street. </p>



<p>Now think of it in terms of the people you meet in the midst of theology debates, Facebook quarrels, and Twitter threads. Think of it with regard to the people you consider theological off base. (Do you love someone because you think you can convince them to change their view, or do you love them regardless of their theological views?) Think of it with regard to people living in the U.S. illegally. Think of it in terms of people you dislike. Do you love liberals AND conservatives? Calvinists AND Arminians? Baptists AND Methodists? Evangelicals AND Atheists? Donald Trump AND Barak Obama? The conservative community AND the LGBT community? </p>



<p>Love believes all things. It&#8217;s not suspicious of everyone. It&#8217;s not assuming the worst of everyone. It&#8217;s not looking for ways that everyone else can serve its interests. It simply believes that each person is worthy of love. And it believes that each person is capable of love. It&#8217;s not afraid of being duped, because its only goal is to give itself away. </p>



<p>Imagine how this one simple concept could transform all of our interactions. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/06/love-believes-all-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1691</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joshua Harris: An Opportunity for Empathy</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/01/joshua-harris-an-opportunity-for-empathy/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/01/joshua-harris-an-opportunity-for-empathy/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 17:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan MacDiarmid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Empathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Harris]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1688</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This last weekend, Joshua Harris posted this on Instagram: &#8220;My heart is full of gratitude. I wish you could see all the messages people sent me after the announcement of my divorce. They are expressions of love though they are saddened or even strongly disapprove of the decision. &#8220;I am learning that no group has [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This last weekend, Joshua Harris posted this on Instagram:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;My heart is full of gratitude. I wish you could see all the messages people sent me after the announcement of my divorce. They are expressions of love though they are saddened or even strongly disapprove of the decision.</p><p>&#8220;I am learning that no group has the market cornered on grace. This week I’ve received grace from Christians, atheists, evangelicals, exvangelicals, straight people, LGBTQ people, and everyone in between. Of course there have also been strong words of rebuke from religious people. While not always pleasant, I know they are seeking to love me. (There have been spiteful, hateful comments that angered and hurt me.)</p><p>&#8220;The information that was left out of our announcement is that I have undergone a massive shift in regard to my faith in Jesus. The popular phrase for this is ‘deconstruction,’ the biblical phrase is ‘falling away.’ By all the measurements that I have for defining a Christian, I am not a Christian. Many people tell me that there is a different way to practice faith and I want to remain open to this, but I’m not there now…</p><p>“To my Christian friends, I am grateful for your prayers. Don’t take it personally if I don’t immediately return calls. I can’t join in your mourning. I don’t view this moment negatively. I feel very much alive, and awake, and surprisingly hopeful. I believe with my sister Julian that, ‘All shall be well, and all manner of thing shall be well.’&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<p>Joshua isn’t the first or last person whose soul-searching journey led them out of the faith. Sometimes when someone leaves it is obvious that they are doing it in a willful desire to justify sin (<a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/06/3-parables-on-grace/">think Prodigal Son</a>). Other times it is about the wearisome nature of the church and its subculture, the dissonant value systems between Christians and their Christ, or the deafening silence of God. In these moments I empathize with Josh’s struggle. </p>



<p>Empathy is an important word. In Romans 12, Paul says, “Rejoice with those who rejoice, and weep with those who weep.” That means empathetic living. Opening yourself up to feel what others feel is a tremendous way to love people.</p>



<p>Sympathy can have a tinge of superiority. <em>I feel sorry for you</em> because you are experiencing pain. Sympathy is not the same as empathy. Empathy says, <em>I feel pain</em> as you feel pain. </p>



<p>The important thing about feeling what others feel is recognizing that you CAN ACTUALLY feel what others feel, and you CAN feel it without condoning ALL of their behaviors or beliefs. </p>



<p>My kids constantly celebrate things and cry about things that are objectively stupid. But I love my kids so I celebrate their stick figure drawings with them and I show empathy for their imaginary bruises (sometimes). The truth is that loving my kids doesn’t mean that I need to think that all the things they celebrate and cry about are wonderful and accurate. It’s enough to see someone I love sad, or someone I love happy. The question is: Can I join them in their pain and joy?</p>



<p>I want to be clear. I do not know Joshua Harris personally, but I am sure that the last several years of his personal life and faith life have been filled with both tears and joy. Tears over the emotional and spiritual turmoil of coming to grips with what you truly believe. His divorce may be amicable, but that doesn’t mean there were not hours upon hours of hurt and pain involved in coming to this decision. Have you ever felt these type of emotions? Have you ever struggled in your relationships? Have you ever changed your mind on something you believed? Have you ever been <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/">scrutinized and/or attacked by strangers</a> who don’t know you? </p>



<p>Objectively, these things suck. You don&#8217;t have to assume a person is sinless to acknowledge that these things suck and to weep with the one who weeps. </p>



<p>Can you weep with Josh? I’m not asking if you can weep about the fact that he is stepping away from his beliefs. Nor am I asking how his situation makes you feel about Christian leaders. I’m asking if you can weep over his pain. Don’t make this about you. This is about him and his wife and his kids. Can you be sad for him about the things that are painful for him?</p>



<p>And now I&#8217;m going to ask for more than most of my readers would probably consider: Josh said he feels awake, alive, and hopeful. Given everything he&#8217;s been experiencing, this may be the first time in a while he&#8217;s felt these things. Can you rejoice with him? </p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;Joshua Harris made a heavy announcement. Will we weep with him as he weeps AND rejoice with him as he rejoices? Or will we make this about our opinions and expectations and lose sight of the person in process?&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CJoshua+Harris+made+a+heavy+announcement.+Will+we+weep+with+him+as+he+weeps+AND+rejoice+with+him+as+he+rejoices%3F+Or+will+we+make+this+about+our+opinions+and+expectations+and+lose+sight+of+the+person+in+process%3F%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-re" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-re&t=%E2%80%9CJoshua+Harris+made+a+heavy+announcement.+Will+we+weep+with+him+as+he+weeps+AND+rejoice+with+him+as+he+rejoices%3F+Or+will+we+make+this+about+our+opinions+and+expectations+and+lose+sight+of+the+person+in+process%3F%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>This one is probably much more difficult to wrap you head around. You may feel that celebrating with Josh is celebrating sin or celebrating walking away from Jesus. (Many readers are doing exactly that, this one is easy for many of you.) I want to be clear, I do not believe the Bible calls us to celebrate sin. So without celebrating sin, is it possible to rejoice in the journey that Joshua is on? Is it okay to be hopeful for him? Is it okay to celebrate some of the freedom he now feels from the religious expectation that has likely oppressed him his entire life? The freedom of finally being honest about what he believes and the state of his marriage? It is truly a soul-crushing endeavor to be living a lie. He must feel free in this moment. He seems excited. I am happy for him. Not happy that he &#8220;fell away;&#8221; happy that the burdens and expectations saddled upon him have been lifted and that possibilities for the future are wide open. I pray blessings upon Joshua Harris. I want good things for him.</p>



<p>To be clear, in my paradigm, that means I also pray that he comes to see that Jesus was not the source of his frustration: <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/04/05/the-end-of-religion/">religion was</a>. I pray he comes to know the easy and light burden of Christ in new ways. I pray God works all these things for his good. But that’s what I want for him. Empathy doesn’t start there. Empathy begins by listening and understanding him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/08/01/joshua-harris-an-opportunity-for-empathy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1688</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
