<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rick Warren &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<atom:link href="http://jackasstheology.com/tag/rick-warren/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<description>For Love, Joy, Peace, and Basic Human Dignity</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 05:56:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-LOGO_BLK_BG_Square.jpg?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Rick Warren &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">156140201</site>	<item>
		<title>Watchdog Theology</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 06:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rick Warren]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1282</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Be careful who you associate with. Stay away from those people—and teachers in particular—who are spreading dangerous doctrine. It would be great if everyone stuck to biblical truth, but that&#8217;s not the case, so we have to be ready to break company with those who are outside the bounds of orthodoxy. It&#8217;s clearly good advice—it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Be careful who you associate with. Stay away from those people—and teachers in particular—who are spreading dangerous doctrine. It would be great if everyone stuck to biblical truth, but that&#8217;s not the case, so we have to be ready to break company with those who are outside the bounds of orthodoxy.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s clearly good advice—it&#8217;s biblical after all—and we all believe it.</p>



<p>But Jesus didn&#8217;t.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In his day, Jesus was accused of being morally loose. Why? Because he hung out with people who were morally loose (Matt. 11:19). He &#8220;associated with&#8221; them. Jesus was pretty strong against the Pharisees for being false teachers, but he didn&#8217;t shun them. We see Jesus eating in their homes (Luke 14) and meeting with them for theological discussion (John 3).</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">“Jesus didn’t divide the way we do. He wasn’t afraid of who he was seen with or who others would assume he was partnering with. Yet this drives much of Evangelicalism.”<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CJesus+didn%E2%80%99t+divide+the+way+we+do.+He+wasn%E2%80%99t+afraid+of+who+he+was+seen+with+or+who+others+would+assume+he+was+partnering+with.+Yet+this+drives+much+of+Evangelicalism.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-kG" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-kG&t=%E2%80%9CJesus+didn%E2%80%99t+divide+the+way+we+do.+He+wasn%E2%80%99t+afraid+of+who+he+was+seen+with+or+who+others+would+assume+he+was+partnering+with.+Yet+this+drives+much+of+Evangelicalism.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>Bottom line: Jesus didn&#8217;t do the kind of dividing we tend to feel is our biblical obligation. He said strong things to people, but he wasn&#8217;t afraid of who he was seen with or who other people would assume he was forging partnerships and sharing a lifestyle with. Yet this drives much of Evangelicalism.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve seen Romans 16:17 flying around recently as a warning against associating with people who teach false doctrine:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I appeal to you, brothers, to watch out for those who cause divisions and create obstacles contrary to the doctrine that you have been taught; avoid them. For such persons do not serve our Lord Christ, but their own appetites, and by smooth talk and flattery they deceive the hearts of the naive. For your obedience is known to all, so that I rejoice over you, but I want you to be wise as to what is good and innocent as to what is evil.</p></blockquote>



<p>Pretty straightforward, right? But read it again. It doesn&#8217;t at all say what I&#8217;ve always assumed it says. Paul isn&#8217;t telling us to divide from people who disagree with us theologically. What does he say? He tells us to avoid people who cause divisions and create obstacles! I don&#8217;t see how to take this other than as a warning&nbsp;<em>against the very people who are constantly warning us</em>about people who teach different doctrine. Am I missing something? Or is that just what it says?</p>



<p>Some of the watchdog theologians I have read seem to be experts in identifying dangerous doctrine or doctrine that may not seem terrible in itself but that <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/04/the-conservative-jackass/">leads down a dangerous path</a>. I wonder what this means in connection to Paul&#8217;s statement to &#8220;be wise as to what is good and innocent as to what is evil.&#8221; Is this just Paul’s way of saying focus on the positive?</p>



<p>The truth is, I have been this watchdog theologian. If you had mentioned Rick Warren in my presence several years ago, I would have given you several reasons why his ministry was deficient. Dangerous even. Guess how many of Rick Warren&#8217;s sermons I had heard or how many of his books I had read? Zero. I literally knew nothing about him firsthand, but I was in this watchdog culture that taught me that he was dangerous.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I barked along.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been devastated when friends turned charismatic. I no longer considered them ministry partners. I&#8217;ve prayed for friends who identified themselves as—dare I say it?—Arminian.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I followed many in my watchdog crowd in taking shots at the &#8220;Emerging Church&#8221;—even years after it stopped existing in recognizable form. I can&#8217;t tell you how many books I&#8217;ve read&nbsp;<em>just because I knew I would disagree with them</em>and wanted to be able to warn people about the dangers therein.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am the watchdog theologian. I still have this knee-jerk impulse to bark at certain groups.</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">“In my former life, warnings against false teaching were infinitely more important than calls to unity. But I completely missed how much the New Testament emphasizes unity.”<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CIn+my+former+life%2C+warnings+against+false+teaching+were+infinitely+more+important+than+calls+to+unity.+But+I+completely+missed+how+much+the+New+Testament+emphasizes+unity.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-kG" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-kG&t=%E2%80%9CIn+my+former+life%2C+warnings+against+false+teaching+were+infinitely+more+important+than+calls+to+unity.+But+I+completely+missed+how+much+the+New+Testament+emphasizes+unity.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>But I&#8217;m beginning to see that some of the passages I&#8217;ve used to justify this approach don&#8217;t say what I thought they said. I&#8217;m beginning to see that <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/11/the-feast/">unity is a FAR bigger deal</a> in the New Testament than I ever would have imagined. In my former life, the warnings against false teaching were infinitely more important than admonitions to be unified. I&#8217;d make statements like, &#8220;There can&#8217;t be any unity without the truth.&#8221; I was being a jackass.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know how it all works. I’m still learning, processing, and discussing. But I know unity is worth working toward. And for the first time in my life I&#8217;m trying to take seriously Paul&#8217;s warning to avoid those who <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/15/farewell-francis-chan/">cause divisions</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/03/28/watchdog-theology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1282</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
