<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Limitations &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<atom:link href="http://jackasstheology.com/tag/limitations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<description>For Love, Joy, Peace, and Basic Human Dignity</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 15:09:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-LOGO_BLK_BG_Square.jpg?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Limitations &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">156140201</site>	<item>
		<title>Superhuman Jackass Guy</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/18/superhuman-jackass-guy/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/18/superhuman-jackass-guy/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan MacDiarmid]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bradley Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Limitations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Limitless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sin]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=831</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I have a lot of people come up to me and say, “I love what you said, but I’m not like that.” My friend West told me about a sermon he preached where he said something along these lines: “We all think we do our own thing, but look how many of us are wearing [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I have a lot of people come up to me and say, “I love what you said, but I’m not like that.”</p>



<p>My friend West told me about a sermon he preached where he said something along these lines: “We all think we do our own thing, but look how many of us are wearing black North Face jackets. We didn’t all independently decide this would be a great jacket, we wear it because we saw other people wearing it.” He said that after the sermon, people came up to him wearing black North Face jackets, explaining, “This was a gift, I didn’t pick it out myself!” I call this person super human guy.</p>



<p>I understand super human guy because I am super human guy. This is how I have lived most of my Christian life. I used to even think to myself, “How can I figure out the exact right rhythm so that I read my Bible, share Jesus with my neighbor, love everyone with perfection, be the perfect father, be extraordinarily patient and extraordinarily kind, be extraordinarily bold, extraordinarily brave? I will never be a hypocrite. I will never be a Pharisee. I will never be part of the problem. No lust. No greed. No flaw guy.” In other words, I wanted to be super human guy, making it clear to everyone why I’m not the problem. </p>



<p>I really have a problem admitting my limitations. And
I’m not the only one. Yeah, we know all have sinned and fall short. All
Christians acknowledge that. I’m talking about something different though: learning
to be comfortable with our limitations. Not just our physical limitations in
time and space, but our limitations in understanding, comprehending, and
emoting. Our inability to actually discern and know and handle truth in
objective ways, without going on the defensive. Can I live in such a way that
it&#8217;s not offensive to know I am severely limited, flawed, and often wrong?&nbsp; </p>



<p>Adam and Eve thought they could be limitless even
before Bradley Cooper&#8217;s magic little pill. They thought that if they had the
knowledge of Good and Evil they could use it, control it, harness it; they thought
they could discern and not be deceived, because after all, doesn’t knowledge
help us avoid deception?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=696%2C348" alt="" class="wp-image-832" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=1024%2C512 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=300%2C150 300w, https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=768%2C384 768w, https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=696%2C348 696w, https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?w=1068 1068w, https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/10-Limitless.jpg?resize=840%2C420 840w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Bradley Cooper in <em>Limitless</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Super human guy is the biggest of all jackasses, because super human guy hasn’t ignored part of the Bible, he has ignored ALL of it. Humans are limited, unable to be God. Absolutely reliant. Remember the analogy that Paul used in 1 Corinthians 12? That we are all pieces of a Body? Which may in fact mean that no matter what you say, no matter how solid the New Year&#8217;s Resolution strategy, you are limited guy (or gal). There is no superman here.</p>



<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;If you claim you&#8217;re not a jackass, you&#8217;re claiming to be God: unlimited in your ability to love, to discern accurately. No manipulation, tantrums, prejudice, greed. But that person is God. And you’re not him.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CIf+you+claim+you%E2%80%99re+not+a+jackass%2C+you%E2%80%99re+claiming+to+be+God%3A+unlimited+in+your+ability+to+love%2C+to+discern+accurately.+No+manipulation%2C+tantrums%2C+prejudice%2C+greed.+But+that+person+is+God.+And+you%E2%80%99re+not+him.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-dp" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-dp&t=%E2%80%9CIf+you+claim+you%E2%80%99re+not+a+jackass%2C+you%E2%80%99re+claiming+to+be+God%3A+unlimited+in+your+ability+to+love%2C+to+discern+accurately.+No+manipulation%2C+tantrums%2C+prejudice%2C+greed.+But+that+person+is+God.+And+you%E2%80%99re+not+him.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>We like to think, “Sure, I’m less than perfect. But
I&#8217;m not the problem.” But “less than perfect” is just a euphemism. Our world
isn’t messed up because we’re &#8220;less than perfect.” It&#8217;s the REALLY bad stuff
that has ruined our world. Like wanting sex with someone else’s spouse,
refusing to forgive even when someone is begging for it. Hording things while
other humans starve. Bullying the weak. That’s what ruins the world. The pain
in this world exists because of big time jackasses. So it isn&#8217;t just that I “missed
the mark” (a euphemism for sin), as though I’m not really bad and couldn’t be
the real problem. It’s more like Vice President Cheney’s hunting accident,
where he missed the target (a duck) and instead hit his hunting buddy in the
face. His aim may not have been that far off, but it not a small problem, it’s a
big problem. </p>



<p>And here’s the thing: I&#8217;m the big problem. So are
you!</p>



<p>If you claim that you are not a jackass, you are
claiming to be God: Unlimited in your ability to love. Unlimited in your
ability to discern accurately at all times. Unlimited in your emotional
response to horrible situations. No emotional manipulation, no childish fits,
no temper tantrums, no prejudice, no faulty assumptions. No lust. No greed. No
mistake guy. Superman guy. But that guy is God. And you’re not him.</p>



<p>Limitation is human. Embrace it. It’s even a huge
part of the solution. What if limitation wasn’t a problem to be overcome, but
actually part of the solution? Without limitation we are all our own gods and
an absolute bloody mess. What if we are limited ON PURPOSE? What if our
limitations aren&#8217;t supposed to all be overcome, but stand as reminders of our
NEED? Constantly pointing us to our need for God, and our need for OTHERS.</p>



<p>The comments are open, so feel free to tell me why you didn’t pick your black North Face jacket because everyone else likes them. Tell me why you’re not the super human jackass guy… </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/02/18/superhuman-jackass-guy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">831</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
