<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Francis Schaeffer &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<atom:link href="http://jackasstheology.com/tag/francis-schaeffer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<description>For Love, Joy, Peace, and Basic Human Dignity</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 03:51:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/jackasstheology.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-LOGO_BLK_BG_Square.jpg?fit=32%2C32</url>
	<title>Francis Schaeffer &#8211; Jackass Theology</title>
	<link>http://jackasstheology.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">156140201</site>	<item>
		<title>If We Cared More, We&#8217;d Fight Less</title>
		<link>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/</link>
				<comments>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Beuving]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Francis Schaeffer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soren Kierkegaard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jackasstheology.com/?p=1722</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[You might think we fight so much because we all care too much. But I&#8217;m convinced it&#8217;s the opposite. And it&#8217;s a Kierkegaard quote that makes me think this. In one of his journals, he wrote: &#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>You might think we fight so much because we all care too much. But I&#8217;m convinced it&#8217;s the opposite. And it&#8217;s a Kierkegaard quote that makes me think this. In one of his journals, he wrote:</p>



<p>&#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must know… It is a question of understanding my destiny, of seeing what God really wants me to do; the thing is to find a truth which is for me, to find the idea for which I am willing to live and die. And what use here would it be if I were to discover a so-called objective truth, or if I worked my way through the philosophers&#8217; systems and were able to call them all to account on request, point out inconsistencies in every single circle? …What use would it be if truth were to stand there before me, cold and naked, not caring whether I acknowledged it or not, and inducing an anxious shudder rather than trusting devotion? Certainly I won&#8217;t deny that I still accept an imperative of knowledge and that one can also be influenced by it, but then it must be taken up alive in me, and this is what I now see as the main point. It is this my soul thirsts for as the African deserts thirst for water.&#8221;</p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">Kierkegaard: &#8220;What I really need is to be clear about what I am to do, not about what I must know…to find a truth which is for me, to find the idea for which I am willing to live and die.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Kierkegaard%3A+%E2%80%9CWhat+I+really+need+is+to+be+clear+about+what+I+am+to+do%2C+not+about+what+I+must+know%E2%80%A6to+find+a+truth+which+is+for+me%2C+to+find+the+idea+for+which+I+am+willing+to+live+and+die.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM&t=Kierkegaard%3A+%E2%80%9CWhat+I+really+need+is+to+be+clear+about+what+I+am+to+do%2C+not+about+what+I+must+know%E2%80%A6to+find+a+truth+which+is+for+me%2C+to+find+the+idea+for+which+I+am+willing+to+live+and+die.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>Kierkegaard makes me wonder if a major problem in our discourteous theological debates is that we don&#8217;t care enough. Maybe that sounds crazy. Our debates seem passionate. The level of disagreement and our unwillingness to budge or consider where someone else is coming from seem to be symptoms of caring too much. But I wonder…</p>



<p>Maybe our problem is that we treat the truth as a thing that &#8220;stands there before us, cold and naked.&#8221; In this paradigm, the truth is something purely external, something set off to the side. It can be seen, acknowledged, assented to, but it&#8217;s not within us, doing the difficult work of transforming us. If the truth is like a list of rules printed out and displayed on a wall, then it can be applied and wielded legalistically. Weaponistically. In this model, we look at the truth externally as we sit around referencing &#8220;common sense&#8221; and criticizing everyone because &#8220;only an idiot could see things differently.&#8221;</p>



<p>Here is precisely where Kierkegaard&#8217;s pursuit could help us so much. Because truth is not meant merely to produce an &#8220;anxious shudder&#8221; within us. It&#8217;s meant to produce &#8220;trusting devotion.&#8221; It&#8217;s not about finding the cold, dead list of words that we will judge everyone by. It&#8217;s about finding a truth that so shapes our internal lives that it is true objectively, and also subjectively. It is true in reality, but—significantly—it is also true FOR ME. That&#8217;s not relativism, that&#8217;s heart-appropriated, deep-seated ownership of the truth. It&#8217;s the refusal to be a &#8220;hearer of the Word&#8221; only, but rather a &#8220;doer of the Word&#8221; (see James 1:22). </p>



<p>What if we stopped policing comments and diving into debates over matters where the truth has not so purchased our souls that we are being shaped by it at the deepest level? What if we disciplined ourselves to <a href="http://jackasstheology.com/2019/05/20/have-fewer-opinions/">have fewer opinions</a> and instead threw ourselves into growing more passionate for the realities of Jesus and his gospel? </p>


<span class="epq-pull-quote epq-pull-quote-default epq-right-align">&#8220;I suspect that much of the vitriol we spew and encounter over theological debates comes from a deep-seated insecurity.&#8221;<div class="epq-social-share-icons"><a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=%E2%80%9CI+suspect+that+much+of+the+vitriol+we+spew+and+encounter+over+theological+debates+comes+from+a+deep-seated+insecurity.%E2%80%9D&url=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM" class="epq-twitter" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-twitter"></span></a><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https://wp.me/paz9cl-rM&t=%E2%80%9CI+suspect+that+much+of+the+vitriol+we+spew+and+encounter+over+theological+debates+comes+from+a+deep-seated+insecurity.%E2%80%9D" class="epq-facebook" target="_blank"><span class="dashicons dashicons-facebook-alt"></span></a></div></span>



<p>I honestly think this would change the Church. I suspect that much of the vitriol we spew and encounter over theological debates comes from a deep-seated insecurity. We&#8217;re not confident in our view of the truth, we&#8217;re worried that someone else is going to see things differently or devalue our perspective, so we lash out because we&#8217;re afraid a simple explanation of our beliefs won&#8217;t be enough. But so what if it&#8217;s not enough? Why do we need everyone to agree with us? The answer is that we don&#8217;t. If the truth matters so much to us in a certain area that it has changed and is changing us, we can share that truth winsomely without the desperation and aggression that characterizes the fearful.</p>



<p>I have always loved a certain line in Francis Schaeffer&#8217;s book <em><a href="https://amzn.to/2NLWHNz">Art and the Bible</a>.</em> After detailing the biblical case for making art that doesn&#8217;t need to be overtly religious, he says  &#8220;When you begin to understand this sort of thing, suddenly you can begin to breathe, and all the terrible pressure that has been put on us by making art something less than spiritual suddenly begins to disappear. And with this truth comes beauty and with this beauty a freedom before God.&#8221; He&#8217;s talking to artists, but I think it fits here as well. When we begin to see the ways a certain truth is true not just in general, but specifically in me, then there comes the freedom of confidence and security. </p>



<p>We need to start caring more so we can start fighting less. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://jackasstheology.com/2019/09/05/if-we-cared-more-wed-fight-less/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1722</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
